Tan Junhao

Jhaotan91@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/jhaotan (+65) 8223 2612

About

9 Years of experience in automation tools with multiple recognition from various employers. Proven track record in automating any line of business processes from HR / Customer Service / Operations. Keen to pick up new skills. Enjoy working as a team.

Skills

Programming Language		Application Areas	Banking Knowledge	
Excel (VBA) MS Access R SQL Batch Script HTML AWS (Cloud) Arduino		 Database Data Migration Web Scraping Email Processing Internet-Of-Things 	 2nd line Operational Risk Mgmt. 1st line Operational Risk Mgmt. Corporate Banking Products Wealth Mgmt. Investment Products Operations 	

Work Experience

DBS Bank Jan 2018 – Present

Risk Controller – Institutional Banking Operations 1st Line - [Risk Management]

- ➤ In-charge of Management Reporting for SG Institutional Banking (4 Departments) includes:
 - Cash Products: TT / MEPS
 - Trade Finance: Letter of credit / Factoring
 - o Loan Products: Hire purchase / Loan Agency
 - Custodial Services
- Perform assurance to monitor that operations meets SLA and detect irregularities in transactions

BNP Paribas Oct 2017 – Jan 2018

Product Development Assistant – Investment Services

Develop system to monitor & update the risk score of investment products (Bonds / Equities / Funds) to ensure regulatory compliance w.r.t. products RMs can sell to customers.

Freelance Programming

Feb 2017 - Jan 2018

Create custom solutions for organizations. Key Projects include:

- On-site QR Code Registration (Client: Event Company)
 - Created a registration system from online sign-up to onsite self-registration.
- ➤ HR Questionnaire software (Client: HR Department)
 - Help HR to provide interviewers a set of tailored questions by inputting certain parameters

United Overseas Bank (UOB)

Feb 2016 - Jan 2017

Officer II – Group Operational Risk Management 2nd Line - [Risk Management]

- Work with stakeholders to accurately standardize all 18,000 records of UOB Singapore & Overseas Subsidiary's Key Process, Risk & Control (PRC) & Key Operational Risk Indicators (KORI).
- Assist in the testing/migration/development of Governance Risk & Control (GRC) System used for tracking bank-wide Operational Risk.
- ➤ Develop system to give oversight on progress of Risk Control Self Assurance (RCSA) Testing to help ensure testing is completed within the stipulated period.

Ministry of Defense (MINDEF)

Nov 2011 – Dec 2013

National Service – Career Development, MEPC – [HR]

- ➤ Use multiple data-points to identify potential candidates from a population of 5000 army land-based Military Experts for scholarship
- ➤ Liaise between different training schools & participants for 8 different career advancement courses.
- ➤ Lead a team of 4 people to develop the Career Planning System used by Career Managers to provide better quality & comprehensive career proposals for army regulars.

Education

SP, Specialist Diploma in Digital Technologies for a Smart City	Apr 2019 – Present
Coursework – Cloud Computing, R Programming, IOT, Arduino	
RMIT, Bachelor of Business (Economics and Finance)	Jan 2014 - Nov 2015
15 Modules – 10 High Distinctions and 3 Distinctions	
SP, Diploma in Financial Informatics	Apr 2008 - May 2011
Graduating GPA: 3.467	

Awards & Recognitions & Other Certification

	Completed Wiley Certified Data Analyst [Certificate]	Jan 2019 – Apr 2019
	Awarded Living Our Values (LOV) Award during UOB [Award]	Oct 2016
\triangleright	Awarded rank of Corporal-First Class during National Service [Awa	rd] Dec 2013
	Awarded Distinction during internship in DBS [Award]	Feb 2011